japanican.com 2012-09-03

# Privacy Policy - JAPANiCAN

As a member of the JTB Group, JTB Global Marketing & Travel has developed a corporate philosophy focused on introducing the allure of Japan to the world by creating a multitude of valuable and meaningful experiences. While conducting business, we also strive to support global communication and the realization of a peaceful, eco-friendly society.

Based on this philosophy, our fundamental policy is to use our solution know-how nurtured as a DMC (Destination Management Company) in Japan and Asia to sincerely provide the best products with the best service for companies and events through our MICE (Meeting, Incentive, Conference and Event) business, SIT (Special Interest Tour) and package tours for overseas visitors. By continuously working to be No. 1 in terms of customer satisfaction, we strive to be fair and just in our corporate activities, place the greatest importance in earning the trust of our customers and corporate partners, and work to improve our corporate value through continuous innovation in our operations.

We see the reliable protection of personal information of our customers and others who have business with our company as indispensable in the implementation of this philosophy and fundamental policy, prompting us to enact the following:

1. | We have developed a personal information management system based on the JIS Q 15001 Standard, and ensured the strict adherence by management and all employees.  
---|---  
2. | We will conduct the collection, usage, and provision of personal information following the personal information management system above legally and fairly and use personal information for work-related purposes only.  
3. | We will take organizational, technical, and rational preventive and corrective measures to mitigate the risk of illegal access, loss, destruction, and leak of all personal information handled by our company.  
4. | We will consider methods of appropriately and quickly handling any complaints or questions from individuals concerning their own personal information.  
5. | We will strictly follow all laws, guidelines, social norms, and public standards regarding personal information will be strictly followed.  
6. | Our personal information management system is regularly audited and continuously improved.  

February 27, 2007 (Established)  
June 21, 2012 (Revised)  
JTB Global Marketing & Travel  
Hisanori Zama, President & CEO 

Personal Protection Section  
Phone Number: 03-5796-5400 

How We Handle Personal Information

In accordance with the Personal Information Protection Act and JTB Global Marketing & Travel Personal Information Protection Policy, JTB Global Marketing & Travel (below, JTBGMT) handles and works to protect the personal information of customers as follows. 

1\. Customer Personal Information Kept by JTBGMT

JTBGMT keeps a portion of personal information provided by customers in travel requests and other transactions as personal data. 

2\. Reasons for Use of Customer Personal Information

JTBGMT and its designated travel businesses (branches) will use personal information provided in travel purchase forms to contact customers, as well as when necessary in the performance of our travel and other services as requested by the customer, including the arrangement of transportation and accommodations (as listed in the agreement).

* In addition, JTBGMT will use customer personal information...

･ | To respond to inquiries  
---|---  
･ | To process credit card payments for products or services  
･ | To provide information on products, services, and campaigns offered by JTBGMT and related companies  
･ | To request opinions and impressions after participating in travel  
･ | To request participation in questionnaires  
･ | To offer special services  
･ | To create statistical data  
  
3\. Handling of Personal Information Related to Credit Cards Used for Internet Purchases

JTB Global Marketing & Travel Inc. will use the personal information of customers related to credit cards used to pay for products or services over the internet.  
**Name of Collector of Credit Card Data**  
JTB Global Marketing & Travel Inc.   
**Outside Consignment of Payment Processing**  
JTB Global Marketing & Travel consigns all operations necessary to process payments for products or services purchased via the internet by credit card to outside companies.   
**Consignment Company**  
i.JTB Corp.  
**Retention Period**  
The personal information related to credit card data is saved for 13 months after which it is erased. 

4\. Sensitive Information

JTBGMT does not collect, use or provide information to third parties on political opinions, faith (religion, philosophy, or creed), race or ethnicity, lineage or place of birth, medical treatment or sexual history, or criminal history, except where permitted by law. Also, when sensitive information is collected, used, or provided to a third party, JTBGMT takes special care in its handling so as not to collect, use, or provide information in a way that is not in accordance with the law. 

5\. Providing Customer Personal Information to Third Parties

･ JTBGMT will provide in electronic form a customer’s name, gender, age, address, phone number, e-mail address, passport number, and credit card number to transportation, accommodation, and insurance companies as necessary to arrange and provide purchased travel services, or as necessary to fulfill travel agreements or complete insurance formalities to securitize costs when accidents occur.

･ JTBGMT may provide customer personal information in our possession to souvenir stores to facilitate shopping by customers at their destination. In such cases, the customer’s name, passport number and flight number will be provided electronically. If you do not wish for your information to be provided to these businesses, please inform the branch where you purchased the travel before departure. 

6\. Consignment of Customer Personal Information

JTBGMT may consign personal information to complete formalities for traveling abroad as well as perform procedures necessary to provide requested travel and other services. When consigning the information, JTBGMT will choose a consignee using company standards, enter into a contract with the consignee for protecting personal information, and audit their practices to ensure the proper handling of personal information. 

7\. Collection and Use of Customer Personal Information

JTBGMT handles the collection and use of customer personal information as follows: 

(1) | Customers are presented with a clearly worded policy on the purpose of collection and types of use in pamphlets and travel request forms, and permission for use and collection is sought.  
---|---  
(2) | If the customer does not agree, information is only collected, not used.  
(3) | When the information is provided to data storage companies or third parties, customers will be notified, and permission will be sought.  
(4) | When the customer is a minor, the permission of the customer’s parent or guardian will be sought.  
(5) | Though customers are free to choose whether or not to provide any or all types of personal information when requesting travel services or information, there are instances where JTBGMT will not be able to contact the customer or complete procedures necessary to provide the requested services when some or all information is not provided, and thus will not be able to accept the requests for services from the customer.  
(6) | In order to simplify customer purchases in the future, JTBGMT and members of the JTB Group listed below may share information, but in these cases, the information will be strictly managed and stored.  

♦ | JTB Corp.  
---|---  
♦ | JTB Hokkaido Corp.  
♦ | JTB Tohoku Corp.  
♦ | JTB Kanto Corp.  
♦ | JTB Metropolitan Corp.  
♦ | JTB Business World Tokyo Corp.  
♦ | JTB Chubu Corp.  
♦ | JTB Tokai Corp.  
♦ | JTB Western Japan Corp.  
♦ | JTB Kansai Corp.  
♦ | JTB Chugoku Shikoku Corp.  
♦ | JTB Kyushu Corp.  
♦ | JTB Okinawa Corp.  
♦ | JTB Media Retailing Corp.  
♦ | i.JTB Corp.  
♦ | JTB Business Innovators Corp.  
♦ | JTB Asia Tourist Corp.  
  
8\. Joint Use of Customer Personal Information

Among the customer personal information that it has acquired, JTBGMT will jointly use names, phone numbers, and e-mail addresses with the group companies below at the minimum extent necessary to contact customers. The group companies will use this information for their own sales activities, simplification of customer orders, sending information on products, and sending purchased products. 

Company Name |  **Address**  
---|---  
JTB Corp. |  2-3-11 Higashi Shinagawa Shinagawa-ku, Tokyo  
JTB Hokkaido Corp. |  Urban Net Sapporo Building, 8th Fl 6-1-2 Kita Ichijo Chuo-ku, Sapporo  
JTB Kanto Corp. |  11-2 Shin Toshin Chuo-ku, Saitama  
JTB Metropolitan Corp. |  4F IK Bldg, 2-24-9 Kamiosaki, Shinagawa-ku, Tokyo  
JTB Business World Tokyo Corp. |  26F Shinjuku Park Tower, 3-7-1 Nishishinjuku, Shinjuku-ku, Tokyo  
JTB Chubu Corp. |  1-1-4 Meieki Nakamura-ku, Nagoya  
JTB Tokai Corp. |  1-1-4 Meieki Nakamura-ku, Nagoya  
JTB Western Japan Corp. |  2-1-25 Kyutaro-machi Chuo-ku, Osaka  
JTB Kansai Corp. |  2-5-10 Sonezaki Kita-ku, Osaka  
JTB Chugoku Shikoku Corp. |  7-19 Hondori Naka-ku, Hiroshima  
JTB Kyushu Corp. |  New KBC Building, 5th F; 1-1-35 Nagahama Chuo-ku, Fukuoka  
JTB Okinawa Corp. |  Shintoshin DL Bldg. 4-19-30 Omoromachi, Nahas-shi, Okinawa  
JTB Media Retailing Corp. |  3F MF Bldg. 4-6-5 Kohinata, Bunkyo-ku, Tokyo  
i.JTB Corp. |  2-3-11 Higashi Shinagawa Shinagawa-ku, Tokyo  
JTB Business Innovators Corp. |  2-3-11 Higashi Shinagawa Shinagawa-ku, Tokyo  
JTB Tohoku Corp. |  Meiji Yasuda Seimei Building, 3rd Fl. 3-7-23 Ichiban-cho Aoba-ku, Sendai  
JTB GAIAREC, INC. |  JTB Building 2-43-19 Minamiikebukuro Toshimaku, Tokyo  
PTS Corp. |  PTS Corp. 3-13-2 Takada Toshima-ku, Tokyo  
JTB Grand Tours & Services, Inc. |  5-7-20 Jingumae Shibuya-ku, Tokyo  
JTB World Vacations, Inc. |  IK Building 2-24-9 Kami-osaki Shinagawa-ku, Tokyo  
Travel Plaza International, Inc. |  2-1-9 Tomioka Koto-ku, Tokyo  
Travel Plaza International Chubu, Inc. |  3-13-24 Meieki Nakamura-ku, Nagoya  
TPI Western Japan, Inc. |  4-5-20 Minami Honmachi Chuo-ku, Osaka  
JTB Sun & Sun Western Japan Co., Ltd. |  AD Building, 2nd Fl. 2-3-12 Minami Honmachi Chuo-ku, Osaka  
JTB Management Service Corp |  2-3-11 Higashi Shinagawa Shinagawa-ku, Tokyo  
JTB Trading, Inc. |  1-44-10 Sekiguchi, Bunkyo-ku, Tokyo  
JTB Global Assistance, Inc. |  2F, COI Nihonbashihoncho Bldg. 4-13-5, Nihonbashihoncho, Chuo-ku,Tokyo  
JTB Asia Tourist Corp. |  2-3-11, Higashishinagawa, Shinagawa-ku, Tokyo  
  
9\. Cookies

The JTBGMT website uses "cookies" to provide better service and ensure security. Cookies are data files that are stored by websites on customer computers and can be read when the customer visits the site at a later date. Individual cookies can only be read by the website that created them. JTBGMT uses cookies for many website management purposes. For instance, to record the types of information requested by customers and to use that information to automatically fill in fields when the customer visits the site. Most cookies are used only for a single session or visit to the site. They do not contain any information that would allow anybody to contact the customer such as phone numbers, e-mail addresses, or mail addresses. Customers can set their browser to inform them of the placement of cookies or to not permit the placement of any cookies. 

10\. Inquiries, Release, Deletion, and Correction of Customer Personal Information

Anyone who requests that we disclose, delete or destroy, change, stop the use, or stop sharing with third parties their individual customer personal information in our possession will be provided with the necessary steps to do so by contacting the departments listed below. When requested, we will take all necessary measures as set by laws and company regulations without delay.  
If we are unable to comply with all or part of your request, we will provide an explanation.

Please contact the departments below for any issues concerning personal information.

(1) Questions and complaints about the handling of personal information and requests for disclose, deletion or destruction. 

JTB Global Marketing & Travel, Inc., Administration Department  
Address: 2-3-11 Highashi-Shinagawa, Shinagawa-ku, Tokyo  
Hours: 9:30-18:00 (Weekdays)  
Phone: 03-5796-5400 (Not open Saturdays, Sundays, holidays, or 12/30-1/3)

(2) Requests for Corrections, Stop of Usage, and Stop Sharing with Third Parties  
Please contact the branch at which you purchased your trip.  
(Contact information is located on the copy of your application and on the contract.) 

11\. In Circumstances When Personal Information is Leaked

If for some reason JTBGMT personal information is disclosed, we will contact the customer immediately. If necessary, we will temporarily shout down our system to maintain security, or we may promptly announce facts about the situation publicly on our homepage.
